<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Earthwalker on</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/</link><description>Recent content in Earthwalker on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://earthwalker.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://earthwalker.me/consume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/consume/</guid><description>Food Rules vegan Preferences prefer nature things, reduce processed, avoid highly processed replace dry food, for example stir-fry salty peanuts, dry chickpea rice soup is not bad Vegetables:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://earthwalker.me/guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/guidelines/</guid><description>Personal experiences and guidelines.
Community Stay away from online Chinese community that moderators actively engages. Usually they inherit some bad authoritarian models.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://earthwalker.me/lists/film/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/lists/film/</guid><description>Drama Borgo (2023) Cong jin yihou (2024)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://earthwalker.me/lists/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/lists/podcasts/</guid><description>Podcasts that I consume.
Food gastropod.com Self-help The Decision Education Podcast Society Assembly Required with Stacey Abrams Letters from an American Technology Quantum Tech Pod</description></item><item><title>100 Baggers - Christopher W Mayer</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/100-Baggers-Christopher-W-Mayer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/100-Baggers-Christopher-W-Mayer/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Christopher W Mayer Full Title: 100 Baggers Category: #books Highlights CHAPTER 1: INTRODUCING 100-BAGGERS 100 to 1 in the Stock Market by Thomas Phelps.</description></item><item><title>A Life on Our Planet: My Witness Statement and a Vision for the Future - Sir David Attenborough</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/A-Life-on-Our-Planet-My-Witness-Statement-and-a-Vision-for-the-Future-Sir-David-Attenborough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/A-Life-on-Our-Planet-My-Witness-Statement-and-a-Vision-for-the-Future-Sir-David-Attenborough/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Sir David Attenborough Full Title: A Life on Our Planet: My Witness Statement and a Vision for the Future Category: #books Highlights The purpose of copyright is to encourage writers and artists to produce the creative works that enrich our culture.</description></item><item><title>About &amp; Resume</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/about/</guid><description>Profile Vegan.
Works in IT as administration, architecture, and manager from year 2014, with extensive hands-on experience.
Interests climate change, environment protection education innovation, spiritual development, psychology documentary, film, book Languages English: B2 Chinese: native Certificates list of my certificates</description></item><item><title>At Home in the World - Thich Nhat Hanh</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/At-Home-in-the-World-Thich-Nhat-Hanh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/At-Home-in-the-World-Thich-Nhat-Hanh/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Thich Nhat Hanh Full Title: At Home in the World Category: #books Highlights Teaching is not done by talking alone.</description></item><item><title>Books</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/lists/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/lists/books/</guid><description>My book reading list.
Anthropology Living Color: The Biological and Social Meaning of Skin Color The Horse, the Wheel, and Language: How Bronze-Age Riders from the Eurasian Steppes Shaped the Modern World #must #history A Short History of Humanity: A New History of Old Europe Captives: How Stolen People Changed the World Gods of the Upper Air: How a Circle of Renegade Anthropologists Reinvented Race, Sex, and Gender in the Twentieth Century Routes: Travel and Translation in the Late Twentieth Century In Search of Respect: Selling Crack in El Barrio The Predicament of Culture: Twentieth-Century Ethnography, Literature, and Art People of the Sea: Identity and Descent among the Vezo of Madagascar 辶反田野：人類學異托邦故事集 #fiction #stories 異溫層迷航記【芭樂人類學2】 #field Claude Levi-Strauss: The Father of Modern Anthropology #people My Life as a Spy: Investigations in a Secret Police File #memoir Ultrasociety: How 10,000 Years of War Made Humans the Greatest Cooperators on Earth Men: Evolutionary and Life History (Richard G.</description></item><item><title>Brief Answers to the Big Questions - Stephen Hawking</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Brief-Answers-to-the-Big-Questions-Stephen-Hawking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Brief-Answers-to-the-Big-Questions-Stephen-Hawking/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Stephen Hawking Full Title: Brief Answers to the Big Questions Category: #books Highlights Foreword Eddie Redmayne He also insisted that I call him Stephen and stop referring to him as Professor.</description></item><item><title>Burn Book - Kara Swisher</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Burn-Book-Kara-Swisher/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Burn-Book-Kara-Swisher/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Kara Swisher Full Title: Burn Book Category: #books Highlights Praise for Kara Swisher “She has a coffee before bed every night, after midnight.</description></item><item><title>Cambodia</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/posts/Cambodia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/posts/Cambodia/</guid><description>VISA Status 2022.10
Me as a Chinese passport holder, can choose from e-VISA or VISA-on-arrival. E-VISA valid for 3 months and allow stay for up to 30 days.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/contact/</guid><description> Gitlab: https://github.com/etwk Mastodon: https://mastodon.social/web/@earthwalker LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/earthwalker-liu Workaway: https://www.workaway.info/en/workawayer/earthwalker</description></item><item><title>Cross the GFW</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/posts/cross-the-GFW/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/posts/cross-the-GFW/</guid><description>The GFW here refer to the censorship on the Internet between China and outside. It&amp;rsquo;s relatively advanced for quite some years.</description></item><item><title>Debian Server Optimize</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/Debian-server-optimize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/Debian-server-optimize/</guid><description>Overview Debian OS as a server can be optimized in a lot of places, to list some important ones:
Change TCP congestion control to use BBR or others, to improve network connectivity and bandwidth Enlarge file limit This applies to other Linux distribution also.</description></item><item><title>Donations</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/projects/donations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/projects/donations/</guid><description>This is part of conscience spending/consumption.
List of my current and history public donations, for reference to others.
Education Malala Fund Donation page: https://malala.</description></item><item><title>Emotional Labor - Rose Hackman</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Emotional-Labor-Rose-Hackman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Emotional-Labor-Rose-Hackman/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Rose Hackman Full Title: Emotional Labor Category: #books Highlights One of the great problems of history is that the concepts of love and power have usually been contrasted as opposites, polar opposites, so that love is identified with a resignation of power, and power with a denial of love.</description></item><item><title>How to Day Trade - Ross Cameron</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Day-Trade-Ross-Cameron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Day-Trade-Ross-Cameron/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Ross Cameron Full Title: How to Day Trade Category: #books Highlights The Myth and the Reality Day trading is like a magnet that strongly attracts some people and strongly repels others.</description></item><item><title>How to Learn a Foreign Language - Paul Pimsleur Ph.D.</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Learn-a-Foreign-Language-Paul-Pimsleur-Ph.D./</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Learn-a-Foreign-Language-Paul-Pimsleur-Ph.D./</guid><description>Metadata Author: Paul Pimsleur Ph.D. Full Title: How to Learn a Foreign Language Category: #books Highlights Foreword Paul Pimsleur died of a heart attack while he was teaching at the Sorbonne in Paris.</description></item><item><title>How to Stand Up to a Dictator: The Fight for Our Future - Maria Ressa</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Stand-Up-to-a-Dictator-The-Fight-for-Our-Future-Maria-Ressa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Stand-Up-to-a-Dictator-The-Fight-for-Our-Future-Maria-Ressa/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Maria Ressa Full Title: How to Stand Up to a Dictator: The Fight for Our Future Category: #books Highlights Foreword there is no greater tyranny than that which is perpetrated under the shield of the law and in the name of justice.</description></item><item><title>How to Win an Information War - Peter Pomerantsev</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Win-an-Information-War-Peter-Pomerantsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/How-to-Win-an-Information-War-Peter-Pomerantsev/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Peter Pomerantsev Full Title: How to Win an Information War Category: #books Highlights PREFACE THE REAL LIVES OF SEFTON DELMER Sefton Delmer would admit decades later, “I enjoyed singing the German victory songs.</description></item><item><title>Information Doesn't Want to Be - Cory Doctorow</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Information-Doesnt-Want-to-Be-Cory-Doctorow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Information-Doesnt-Want-to-Be-Cory-Doctorow/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Cory Doctorow Full Title: Information Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Want to Be Category: #books Highlights FOREWORD #1 Neil Gaiman what Charles Dickens did, a hundred and fifty years before, when copyright laws meant that his copyrights were worth nothing in the U.</description></item><item><title>Inner Engineering: A Yogi's Guide to Joy - Sadhguru</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Inner-Engineering-A-Yogis-Guide-to-Joy-Sadhguru/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Inner-Engineering-A-Yogis-Guide-to-Joy-Sadhguru/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Sadhguru Full Title: Inner Engineering: A Yogi&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Joy Category: #books Highlights One man’s “magic” is another man’s engineering.</description></item><item><title>International Money Transfer</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/international-money-transfer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/international-money-transfer/</guid><description>Wise A great tool for money in and out internationally, and they are active and adding features continuously.
Receive Physical Card Notes:</description></item><item><title>Joe Biden - Evan Osnos</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Joe-Biden-Evan-Osnos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Joe-Biden-Evan-Osnos/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Evan Osnos Full Title: Joe Biden Category: #books Highlights People pay for what they do, and, still more, for what they have allowed themselves to become.</description></item><item><title>My Certificates</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/certificates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/certificates/</guid><description>Tech Machine Learning Machine Learning Specialization (by Stanford University &amp;amp; DeepLearning.AI)
Security Google Cybersecurity Certificate
Life Driver&amp;rsquo;s License AHA Heardsaver First Aid CPR AED (Oct.</description></item><item><title>Never Split the Difference: Negotiating as if Your Life Depended on It - Chris Voss</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Never-Split-the-Difference-Negotiating-as-if-Your-Life-Depended-on-It-Chris-Voss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Never-Split-the-Difference-Negotiating-as-if-Your-Life-Depended-on-It-Chris-Voss/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Chris Voss Full Title: Never Split the Difference: Negotiating as if Your Life Depended on It Category: #books Highlights integrity (Location 6)</description></item><item><title>No Mud, No Lotus - Thich Nhat Hanh</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/No-Mud-No-Lotus-Thich-Nhat-Hanh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/No-Mud-No-Lotus-Thich-Nhat-Hanh/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Thich Nhat Hanh Full Title: No Mud, No Lotus Category: #books Highlights “Most people are afraid of suffering.</description></item><item><title>No One Belongs Here More Than You - Miranda July</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/No-One-Belongs-Here-More-Than-You-Miranda-July/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/No-One-Belongs-Here-More-Than-You-Miranda-July/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Miranda July Full Title: No One Belongs Here More Than You Category: #books Highlights The Shared Patio People tend to stick to their own size group because it’s easier on the neck.</description></item><item><title>Our Malady - Timothy Snyder</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Our-Malady-Timothy-Snyder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Our-Malady-Timothy-Snyder/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Timothy Snyder Full Title: Our Malady Category: #books Highlights PROLOGUE Solitude and Solidarity Malaise is what we feel when we have a malady.</description></item><item><title>Purchase Good and Bad</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/posts/purchase-good-and-bad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/posts/purchase-good-and-bad/</guid><description>Here I list some of my good and bad purchase decisions.
Good Phone Google Pixel 6 Got this wile I was in China from a seller in Taobao, a little higher compare to purchase directly from Google but saved a lot of time and energy.</description></item><item><title>Scam Me If You Can: Simple Strategies to Outsmart Today's Rip-off Artists - Frank Abagnale</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Scam-Me-If-You-Can-Simple-Strategies-to-Outsmart-Todays-Rip-off-Artists-Frank-Abagnale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Scam-Me-If-You-Can-Simple-Strategies-to-Outsmart-Todays-Rip-off-Artists-Frank-Abagnale/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Frank Abagnale Full Title: Scam Me If You Can: Simple Strategies to Outsmart Today&amp;rsquo;s Rip-off Artists Category: #books Highlights Foreword by Keith Slotter And he was freely available!</description></item><item><title>Setup Local DNS Server</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/setup-local-DNS-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/setup-local-DNS-server/</guid><description>Overview This tutorial is about how to get clean, optimized DNS resolve results by set up a local DNS server. Use China as an example.</description></item><item><title>Setup naiveproxy</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/setup-naiveproxy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/setup-naiveproxy/</guid><description>Overview This tutorial is about how to set up naiveproxy server and client to provide transparent proxy to a local network.</description></item><item><title>Seven And A Half Lessons About The Brain - Lisa Feldman Barrett</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Seven-And-A-Half-Lessons-About-The-Brain-Lisa-Feldman-Barrett/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Seven-And-A-Half-Lessons-About-The-Brain-Lisa-Feldman-Barrett/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Lisa Feldman Barrett Full Title: Seven And A Half Lessons About The Brain Category: #books Highlights Author’s Note The essays don’t tell you what to think about human nature, but they do invite you to think about the kind of human you are or want to be.</description></item><item><title>Seven Brief Lessons on Physics - Carlo Rovelli</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Seven-Brief-Lessons-on-Physics-Carlo-Rovelli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Seven-Brief-Lessons-on-Physics-Carlo-Rovelli/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Carlo Rovelli Full Title: Seven Brief Lessons on Physics Category: #books Highlights Preface science shows us how to better understand the world, but it also reveals to us just how vast is the extent of what is still not known.</description></item><item><title>SSL Certificate</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/SSL-certificate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/tutorials/SSL-certificate/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt provide free SSL certificate:
They even support wildcard certificate! Certificate valid for 90 days. You could obtain or renew certificates automatically or manually.</description></item><item><title>Subscriptions</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/projects/subscriptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/projects/subscriptions/</guid><description>This is part of conscience spending/consumption.
List of my current and history public subscriptions, for reference to others.
News &amp;amp; Media Guardian News &amp;amp; Media Introduction: a long time English media with very good quality and relatively open access.</description></item><item><title>The Autobiography of Martin Luther King, Jr. - Clayborne Carson</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Autobiography-of-Martin-Luther-King-Jr.-Clayborne-Carson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Autobiography-of-Martin-Luther-King-Jr.-Clayborne-Carson/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Clayborne Carson Full Title: The Autobiography of Martin Luther King, Jr. Category: #books Highlights 1 EARLY YEARS He is conscientious in all of his undertakings.</description></item><item><title>The Fight of Our Lives - Iuliia Mendel</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Fight-of-Our-Lives-Iuliia-Mendel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Fight-of-Our-Lives-Iuliia-Mendel/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Iuliia Mendel Full Title: The Fight of Our Lives Category: #books Highlights ILYA KAMINSKY, DEAF REPUBLIC (Location 18)</description></item><item><title>The Internationalists - Alexander Ward</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Internationalists-Alexander-Ward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Internationalists-Alexander-Ward/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Alexander Ward Full Title: The Internationalists Category: #books Highlights Good and evil both increase at compound interest.</description></item><item><title>The Patriarchs - Angela Saini</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Patriarchs-Angela-Saini/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Patriarchs-Angela-Saini/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Angela Saini Full Title: The Patriarchs Category: #books Highlights Praise for The Patriarchs: Sathnam Sanghera, author of Empireland (Location 32)</description></item><item><title>The Road to Unfreedom - Timothy Snyder</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Road-to-Unfreedom-Timothy-Snyder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Road-to-Unfreedom-Timothy-Snyder/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Timothy Snyder Full Title: The Road to Unfreedom Category: #books Highlights For the reporters, the heroes of our time (Location 20)</description></item><item><title>The Showman - Simon Shuster</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Showman-Simon-Shuster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Showman-Simon-Shuster/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Simon Shuster Full Title: The Showman Category: #books Highlights Prologue There were plenty of retirees, hipsters and office workers, young couples on expensive dates, the full range of the middle class that had formed in Ukraine since the collapse of the Soviet Union.</description></item><item><title>The Smallest Lights in the Universe - Sara Seager</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Smallest-Lights-in-the-Universe-Sara-Seager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Smallest-Lights-in-the-Universe-Sara-Seager/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Sara Seager Full Title: The Smallest Lights in the Universe Category: #books Highlights I’d spent my entire life searching for lights in the dark; now I could see only the blackness that surrounded them.</description></item><item><title>The T Guide: Our Trans Experiences and a Celebration of Gender Expression - Gigi Gorgeous, Gottmik</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-T-Guide-Our-Trans-Experiences-and-a-Celebration-of-Gender-Expression-Gigi-Gorgeous-Gottmik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-T-Guide-Our-Trans-Experiences-and-a-Celebration-of-Gender-Expression-Gigi-Gorgeous-Gottmik/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Gigi Gorgeous, Gottmik Full Title: The T Guide: Our Trans Experiences and a Celebration of Gender Expression Category: #books Highlights Introduction A lot of people in this country— and in the world— don’t really understand what it actually means to be trans, or all that the concept of transitioning entails.</description></item><item><title>The Unwomanly Face of War - Svetlana Alexievich</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Unwomanly-Face-of-War-Svetlana-Alexievich/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/The-Unwomanly-Face-of-War-Svetlana-Alexievich/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Svetlana Alexievich Full Title: The Unwomanly Face of War Category: #books Highlights —Already in the fourth century B.</description></item><item><title>Under Pressure: Confronting the Epidemic of Stress and Anxiety in Girls - Lisa Damour</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Under-Pressure-Confronting-the-Epidemic-of-Stress-and-Anxiety-in-Girls-Lisa-Damour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Under-Pressure-Confronting-the-Epidemic-of-Stress-and-Anxiety-in-Girls-Lisa-Damour/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Lisa Damour Full Title: Under Pressure: Confronting the Epidemic of Stress and Anxiety in Girls Category: #books Highlights Introduction girls between the ages of twelve and seventeen are now nearly three times more likely than boys to become depressed.</description></item><item><title>Upwork Scam 2024-02-10</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/posts/Upwork-Scam-2024-02-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/posts/Upwork-Scam-2024-02-10/</guid><description>I have been scammed on 2024-02-10 (Lunar New Year) at Upwork. Direct lost nearly 5000 USD, indirect lost much more. Here are the details.</description></item><item><title>What I'm doing now</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/now/</guid><description>Working https://github.com/etwk</description></item><item><title>What Iranians Want - Arash Azizi</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/What-Iranians-Want-Arash-Azizi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/What-Iranians-Want-Arash-Azizi/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Arash Azizi Full Title: What Iranians Want Category: #books Highlights ‘Oh, of who do I speak?</description></item><item><title>Zelensky: A Biography - Serhii Rudenko</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/Zelensky-A-Biography-Serhii-Rudenko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/Zelensky-A-Biography-Serhii-Rudenko/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Serhii Rudenko Full Title: Zelensky: A Biography Category: #books Highlights Preface Zelensky’s Political Oscar Zelensky’s presidential image was constructed by those around him.</description></item><item><title>出中國記 2022</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/posts/run-from-China-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/posts/run-from-China-2022/</guid><description>筆者在 2022.10 自廣州白雲機場離開中國來到 Cambodia，分享相關經歷。
爲什麽離開中國 希望參加 Vipassana 課程，這是筆者個人成長和心理調整的重要環節，因爲疫情等原因已經耽誤了接近 3 年。 中國沒有中心，非中心的幾個點在網上也關閉了入口需要電話聯係，有些點已經滿員。 希望接受原版英文授課，而非中文二手。 中國環境對類似活動可能相對不友好。 需要出國歷練，呼吸自由空氣。以前算是沒有出國過，像是溫室培養皿裏的植物，在視野、與世界的交互、三觀方面均需歷練。 一個明顯的例子，筆者在社會偏向於收縮，會先看是否有被允許，為白名單模式。法制自由開放的國家是黑名單模式，法律、約定等限定不能做的要嚴格遵守，其它的可以自由做，可能會有摩擦，出現後對應處理或潤滑就行了。 更大程度的脫離原生家庭、國家、文化。 對於中國政府對内對外的很多做法都不認同，用脚投票是最低程度的非常明確的發聲。同時從工資等方面斷絕對中國政府的稅收支持，間接響應勇士的「罷工罷課」號召。 從 2022 年的新冠清零措施感受到巨大的屈辱和壓力，留下來而不做什麽有很强的忍辱偷生的感覺。 爲什麽去 Cambodia 可以約到最近的 Vipassana 課程。 簽證方便辦理，有效期足夠長。 Cambodia 是去東南亞、南亞很多國家的廉價飛行的轉機地點，節約交通費用減少環境污染。 柬埔寨紅色高棉歷史筆者在二十多嵗才瞭解到，非常震撼，是三觀啓蒙、開始勇敢質疑的一個重要節點。需要更多瞭解相關歷史。 出國的準備 常規準備 護照。筆者護照已于 4 年前辦好。現在新辦護照可能會困難很多，受「非必要不出國」政策等的影響，但不是做不了，可嘗試：找必要出國的證明，例如學習；找關係。 通關。很多國家在 2022 年減少了疫情相關的入境限制，例如筆者去 Cambodia 之前看資料說需要在抵達后自費 $5 USD 做抗原檢測，實際不需要，沒有 COVID 檢查。 交通。10 月份出國的機票已比較正常。相對疫情之前還是受限不少，例如去尼泊爾無法走陸路要坐飛機，費用不低。 簽證。聽説發達國家的簽證不好辦，筆者也沒有出國歷史，沒有嘗試。直接網上申請的 Cambodia 的電子旅游簽，方便快速，簽證最好打印 1 張出來。 特殊準備 「非必要不出国」政策。旅游一般被視作非必要，筆者做的準備：預定好課程並打印溝通記錄;申請好 VISA 而不是走落地簽，這樣多少增加一些游説分量。 目的地國家的特殊情況。較多中國人去 Cambodia 等東南亞國家參加賭博、詐騙等活動，警察可能會對這些目的地的出行作勸返。需瞭解這個情況，做好游説準備；能找戶籍所在地開出允許出境的證明最好。 中國機場、火車站等都需要核酸。確保有所需的核酸並結果正常。 出行前 Cambodia e-Visa 出行用品 筆者的想法是極簡背包客 (backpacker)，不配置行李箱，所有行李背負隨身登機。</description></item><item><title>國鎮 - 野夫</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%9C%8B%E9%8E%AE-%E9%87%8E%E5%A4%AB/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%9C%8B%E9%8E%AE-%E9%87%8E%E5%A4%AB/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 野夫 Full Title: 國鎮 Category: #books Highlights 必 須 感 謝 荷 蘭 國 家 文 學 基金 會, 給 了 我 起 心 動 念 開 始 這 部 小 說 的 機 緣。 (Location 2)</description></item><item><title>女神自助餐 - 劉芷妤</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%A5%B3%E7%A5%9E%E8%87%AA%E5%8A%A9%E9%A4%90-%E5%8A%89%E8%8A%B7%E5%A6%A4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%A5%B3%E7%A5%9E%E8%87%AA%E5%8A%A9%E9%A4%90-%E5%8A%89%E8%8A%B7%E5%A6%A4/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 劉芷妤 Full Title: 女神自助餐 Category: #books Highlights 同 學 會 她第一個念頭是逃跑, 第二 個 念 頭 是 用 全身 的 力 氣 禁止 自己 逃跑。 (Location 58)</description></item><item><title>宋氏三姊妹與她們的丈夫：20世紀三位傳奇女子，一部動盪百年的中國現代史 - 張戎 (Jung Chang)</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%AE%8B%E6%B0%8F%E4%B8%89%E5%A7%8A%E5%A6%B9%E8%88%87%E5%A5%B9%E5%80%91%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%88%E5%A4%AB20%E4%B8%96%E7%B4%80%E4%B8%89%E4%BD%8D%E5%82%B3%E5%A5%87%E5%A5%B3%E5%AD%90%E4%B8%80%E9%83%A8%E5%8B%95%E7%9B%AA%E7%99%BE%E5%B9%B4%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%AD%E5%9C%8B%E7%8F%BE%E4%BB%A3%E5%8F%B2-%E5%BC%B5%E6%88%8E-Jung-Chang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%AE%8B%E6%B0%8F%E4%B8%89%E5%A7%8A%E5%A6%B9%E8%88%87%E5%A5%B9%E5%80%91%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%88%E5%A4%AB20%E4%B8%96%E7%B4%80%E4%B8%89%E4%BD%8D%E5%82%B3%E5%A5%87%E5%A5%B3%E5%AD%90%E4%B8%80%E9%83%A8%E5%8B%95%E7%9B%AA%E7%99%BE%E5%B9%B4%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%AD%E5%9C%8B%E7%8F%BE%E4%BB%A3%E5%8F%B2-%E5%BC%B5%E6%88%8E-Jung-Chang/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 張戎 (Jung Chang) Full Title: 宋氏三姊妹與她們的丈夫：20世紀三位傳奇女子，一部動盪百年的中國現代史 Category: #books Highlights 孫 中山 一 八八 六年 自己 走 進 倫 敦 的 中 國 公使 館 後 被扣, 使他 成 為 唯一 有 世界 知名度 的 中 國 革命者, 這 對 他 後 來 被 尊 為「 國 父」 起了 巨大 作用。 (Location 18)</description></item><item><title>宮前町九十番地 - 陳柔縉</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%AE%AE%E5%89%8D%E7%94%BA%E4%B9%9D%E5%8D%81%E7%95%AA%E5%9C%B0-%E9%99%B3%E6%9F%94%E7%B8%89/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E5%AE%AE%E5%89%8D%E7%94%BA%E4%B9%9D%E5%8D%81%E7%95%AA%E5%9C%B0-%E9%99%B3%E6%9F%94%E7%B8%89/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 陳柔縉 Full Title: 宮前町九十番地 Category: #books Highlights 戰 前 照片 常以 附合 方式 把 缺席者 補 上。 (Location 36)</description></item><item><title>慈禧：開啟現代中國的皇太后 - 張戎 (Jung Chang)</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%85%88%E7%A6%A7%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%8F%BE%E4%BB%A3%E4%B8%AD%E5%9C%8B%E7%9A%84%E7%9A%87%E5%A4%AA%E5%90%8E-%E5%BC%B5%E6%88%8E-Jung-Chang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%85%88%E7%A6%A7%E9%96%8B%E5%95%9F%E7%8F%BE%E4%BB%A3%E4%B8%AD%E5%9C%8B%E7%9A%84%E7%9A%87%E5%A4%AA%E5%90%8E-%E5%BC%B5%E6%88%8E-Jung-Chang/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 張戎 (Jung Chang) Full Title: 慈禧：開啟現代中國的皇太后 Category: #books Highlights 美 國 總 統 林肯 派 駐 中 國 的 首任 公使 蒲 安 臣。 任期 結 束 後, 慈禧 任命 他 為 中 國 第一位 赴 歐 美 各 國 特使。 (Location 119)</description></item><item><title>文明的邏輯：人類與風險的博弈 - 陳志武</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%96%87%E6%98%8E%E7%9A%84%E9%82%8F%E8%BC%AF%E4%BA%BA%E9%A1%9E%E8%88%87%E9%A2%A8%E9%9A%AA%E7%9A%84%E5%8D%9A%E5%BC%88-%E9%99%B3%E5%BF%97%E6%AD%A6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%96%87%E6%98%8E%E7%9A%84%E9%82%8F%E8%BC%AF%E4%BA%BA%E9%A1%9E%E8%88%87%E9%A2%A8%E9%9A%AA%E7%9A%84%E5%8D%9A%E5%BC%88-%E9%99%B3%E5%BF%97%E6%AD%A6/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 陳志武 Full Title: 文明的邏輯：人類與風險的博弈 Category: #books Highlights 緒 論 風 險 推 動 的 人 類 文明 這 個 文明 真 實 嗎?</description></item><item><title>毛澤東：鮮為人知的故事 - Jung Chang, Jon Halliday</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%AF%9B%E6%BE%A4%E6%9D%B1%E9%AE%AE%E7%82%BA%E4%BA%BA%E7%9F%A5%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B-Jung-Chang-Jon-Halliday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%AF%9B%E6%BE%A4%E6%9D%B1%E9%AE%AE%E7%82%BA%E4%BA%BA%E7%9F%A5%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B-Jung-Chang-Jon-Halliday/</guid><description>Metadata Author: Jung Chang, Jon Halliday Full Title: 毛澤東：鮮為人知的故事 Category: #books Highlights 修 訂 版 自序 在 剛 剛 解 體 的 前 蘇 聯, 葉 爾 辛 總 統 打 開 了 俄 羅 斯 檔 案 館 的 大 門, 這 是 研究 毛 澤 東 的 史料 寶 庫。 (Location 12)</description></item><item><title>沒有墓碑的草原 - 楊海英</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%B2%92%E6%9C%89%E5%A2%93%E7%A2%91%E7%9A%84%E8%8D%89%E5%8E%9F-%E6%A5%8A%E6%B5%B7%E8%8B%B1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E6%B2%92%E6%9C%89%E5%A2%93%E7%A2%91%E7%9A%84%E8%8D%89%E5%8E%9F-%E6%A5%8A%E6%B5%B7%E8%8B%B1/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 楊海英 Full Title: 沒有墓碑的草原 Category: #books Highlights 楊 海 英 教授 的《 沒 有 墓碑 的 草原》 會 讓 世人 看到, 內 蒙古 問 題 將 和 西藏、 新疆 問 題 一起, 成 為 中 華 帝 國 未 來 的 噩 夢。 ─ ─ 王 力 雄 (Location 37)</description></item><item><title>為幸福而生：在法律秩序中追求平等權利的歷程 - 劉宗坤</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E7%82%BA%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E8%80%8C%E7%94%9F%E5%9C%A8%E6%B3%95%E5%BE%8B%E7%A7%A9%E5%BA%8F%E4%B8%AD%E8%BF%BD%E6%B1%82%E5%B9%B3%E7%AD%89%E6%AC%8A%E5%88%A9%E7%9A%84%E6%AD%B7%E7%A8%8B-%E5%8A%89%E5%AE%97%E5%9D%A4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E7%82%BA%E5%B9%B8%E7%A6%8F%E8%80%8C%E7%94%9F%E5%9C%A8%E6%B3%95%E5%BE%8B%E7%A7%A9%E5%BA%8F%E4%B8%AD%E8%BF%BD%E6%B1%82%E5%B9%B3%E7%AD%89%E6%AC%8A%E5%88%A9%E7%9A%84%E6%AD%B7%E7%A8%8B-%E5%8A%89%E5%AE%97%E5%9D%A4/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 劉宗坤 Full Title: 為幸福而生：在法律秩序中追求平等權利的歷程 Category: #books Highlights 作者 簡 介 不 斷 矯 正 過 往 從 書 本 獲 得的 理 論 知 識 的 偏 頗。 書 本 傳 授 知 識, 也 傳 授 偏 見。 (Location 10)</description></item><item><title>行者思之 - 张思之</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E8%A1%8C%E8%80%85%E6%80%9D%E4%B9%8B-%E5%BC%A0%E6%80%9D%E4%B9%8B/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E8%A1%8C%E8%80%85%E6%80%9D%E4%B9%8B-%E5%BC%A0%E6%80%9D%E4%B9%8B/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 张思之 Full Title: 行者思之 Category: #books Highlights 序:成也不須矜,敗也不須爭 《 王 鼎 鈞 回 憶 錄 四部曲》 (Location 26)</description></item><item><title>鴻：三代中國女人的故事 - 張戎 (Jung Chang)</title><link>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E9%B4%BB%E4%B8%89%E4%BB%A3%E4%B8%AD%E5%9C%8B%E5%A5%B3%E4%BA%BA%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B-%E5%BC%B5%E6%88%8E-Jung-Chang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://earthwalker.me/read/%E9%B4%BB%E4%B8%89%E4%BB%A3%E4%B8%AD%E5%9C%8B%E5%A5%B3%E4%BA%BA%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B-%E5%BC%B5%E6%88%8E-Jung-Chang/</guid><description>Metadata Author: 張戎 (Jung Chang) Full Title: 鴻：三代中國女人的故事 Category: #books Highlights 風 塵 是 我的 伴 侶 海角 是 我的 故 家 (Location 12)</description></item></channel></rss>